Guide to the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, Yale University, Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, Yale University, records of the dean
1900-2010
RU 40
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
116
7473
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, financial records, committee files, minutes, reports, and related materials documenting the activities of the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies (called the School of Forestry prior to 1972). Topics include governance, curriculum, budgets and fund-raising, buildings and properties, camps and experiment stations, research programs, students, personnel, alumni relations, and relations with governmental and forestry organizations. The records include central files of the school and those maintained by the following deans: Henry S. Graves (1900-1911 and 1922-1939), James W. Toumey (1911-1922), Samuel J. Record (1939-1945), George A. Garratt (1946-1965), Francois Mergen (1965-1974), Charles W. H. Foster (1976-1980), John C. Gordon (1983-1992), Jared L. Cohen (1992-1997), and Gus Speth (1997 -).
Yale University. School of Forestry and Environmental Studies
Foster, Charles H. W., 1927-
Garratt, George A. (George Alfred), 1898-1984
Graves, Henry Solon, 1871-1951
Mergen, François, 1925-1989
Record, Samuel J. (Samuel James), 1881-1945
Toumey, James W. (James William), 1865-1932
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 24-A (YRG 24-A), Central records and records of the dean of the Yale School of Forestry.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, 1982-1984, 2006-2008.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale School of Forestry was begun in 1900 through the efforts of two conservationists, Gifford Pinchot (B.A. 1889, LL.D. 1925) and Henry S. Graves (B.A. 1892, LL.D. 1940). The school is the oldest forestry school in the country, and its influence on forestry in the United States and abroad, has become well-established. Though in its early years the school was primarily a professional institution concerned with training general practitioners for timber management, it soon became a major source of faculty members for other schools throughout the country. As the subject of forestry widened to include ecology and the environment, the curriculum also enlarged. In 1972 the name was changed to the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies. The school exists as a professional and scientific school and is organized, primarily, on a graduate basis. The School of Forestry and Environmental Studies conducts field work in a number of school forests located throughout New England.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, financial records, committee files, minutes, reports, and related materials documenting the activities of the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies (called the School of Forestry prior to 1972). Topics include governance, curriculum, budgets and fund-raising, buildings and properties, camps and experiment stations, research programs, students, personnel, alumni relations, and relations with governmental and forestry organizations. The records include central files of the school and those maintained by the following deans: Henry S. Graves (1900-1911 and 1922-1939), James W. Toumey (1911-1922), Samuel J. Record (1939-1945), George A. Garratt (1946-1965), Francois Mergen (1965-1974), Charles W. H. Foster (1976-1980), John C. Gordon (1983-1992), Jared L. Cohen (1992-1997), and Gus Speth (1997 -).
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Conservation of natural resources; Environmental protection; Forest conservation; Forest management; Forestry schools and education; Forests and forestry -- Research; Human ecology -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Forestry and Environmental Studies; Yale University. School of Forestry
- Correspondence and subject files of Henry S. Graves, 1900-1946; Accession 1982-A-010
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - A, 1924-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Adventure Expedition, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Foresters, Society of, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Foresters, Society of: Committee on the Regulation of Private Forests, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American - Scandinavian Foundation, circa 1921 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reports to the President, 1922-1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Appointments, Bureau of, 1928-1939 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Arnold, Benjamin Walworth, Memorial, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - B
    - 1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1932-1940 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Bishop Museum, The, 1932-1939 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Bonbright - Childs Fund, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Botanical Garden, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bowers Fund, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brazilian Exposition, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Budget
    - 1922-1934 (Box 2, Folder 25-36)
    - 1934-1940 (Box 3, Folder 37-42)
  - Budget, Five-Year, circa 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Bursar's Office
    - 1921-1924 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - 1928-1939 (Box 3, Folder 45-47)
  - C, 1932-1939 (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
  - C - G, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Carnegie, Andrew: gift, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Case System, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Chapman, H.H., 1931-1932, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Childs, Starling
    - 1928-1931 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - 1935 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - China, Forestry in, circa 1916 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - D, 1935-1940 (Box 3, Folder 57-58)
  - Den Forest, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - E, 1934-1940 (Box 4, Folder 60-61)
  - Employment of Students, 1920, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Employment of Yale Forestry Students: A Statistical Report, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Endowment: Votes of the Corporation, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Establishment of Various Forest Schools' Historical Data, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Expenses of Students, 1920-1921 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Experiment Station(s) in Forest Research: plans and proposals, 1906 (?) (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - F, 1931-1939 (Box 4, Folder 68-69)
  - Farnam - Ardenghi Estate, 1930-1946 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Field Work: Truck, 1931-1934 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Finances: Projected Needs - Yale Forestry School, 1912-1915 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Financial Campaign, 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Forest Museum (proposed), Undated (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Forest Service, 1929-1939 (Box 4, Folder 75-77)
  - Forester's Sales, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Friendship Tree - Barbara Bayne, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - G, 1933-1939 (Box 5, Folder 80-81)
  - Graduate Advisory Board
    - 1911-1915 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - 1919-1920 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Graduate School
    - circa 1925-1932 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - 1939 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Faculty, Department of Forestry, 1928-1938 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Requirernents for Ph.D., 1927 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Graduate Work in Forestry, A Report, 1926-1927 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - H
    - 1928-1936 (Box 5, Folder 92-94)
    - 1936-1939 (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Hayenmeyer, Loomis A. Conservation of Our Natural Resources, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 95A)
  - Health Department - Yale, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - History of the Forestry School - Pinchot Gift, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 97a)
  - I, 1934-1940 (Box 6, Folder 98-99)
  - J, 1932-1940 (Box 6, Folder 100-101)
  - K, 1929-1939 (Box 6, Folder 102-104)
  - L, 1927-1939 (Box 6, Folder 108-110)
  - M
    - 1923-1932 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - 1935-1939 (Box 7, Folder 112-114)
  - Mc - Mac, 1930-1931 (Box 8, Folder 115)
  - Marsh Hall
    - 1934-1939 (Box 8, Folder 116)
    - Inventories, 1913-1918 (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Military Operations at Yale, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 118)
  - N, 1927-1939 (Box 8, Folder 120-122)
  - N - O (Nicholls, G.E.), 1923-1931 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - Naval Research - Tropical Woods Resistant to Marine Borers, 1935-1938 (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - New Haven Water Company
    - Organization, 1929-1937 (Box 9, Folder 125)
    - Permit to enter Grounds, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - O, 1928-1933 (Box 9, Folder 127-128)
  - Oberlander Trust, 1931-1937 (Box 9, Folder 129-131)
  - P, 1929-1936 (Box 9, Folder 132-133)
  - P - Q, 1933-1939 (Box 9, Folder 134)
  - Pack, Charles Lathrop, 1924-1932 (Box 9, Folder 135)
  - Pack, C.L. and A.N., 1937 (Box 9, Folder 136)
  - Pack (Charles Lathrop) Foundation, 1928-1929 (Box 9, Folder 137)
  - Pack (Charles Lathrop) Prize, 1923-1931 (Box 10, Folder 138)
  - Peabody Museum - Forest School Collection, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 139)
  - Personnel Office - policies etc., circa 1924 (Box 10, Folder 140)
  - Plant Industry, Bureau of, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - President's Office, 1922-1939 (Box 10, Folder 142-145)
  - Provost Correspondence, 1929-1932 (Box 10, Folder 146)
  - Provost's Office, 1932-1939 (Box 10, Folder 147-148)
  - Public Policy - Report of Gifford Pinchot, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 149)
  - Purchases and Requisitions, Bureau of Brown Tickets, 1939-1940 (Box 10, Folder 150-151)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1940 (Box 10, Folder 153)
    - Requisitions, 1938-1940 (Box 10, Folder 154)
  - R
    - 1930-1932 (Box 11, Folder 155)
    - 1934-1939 (Box 11, Folder 156)
  - Reforestation, Meeting - New York, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 158)
  - Robin Hood Society, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - S, 1926-1939 (Box 12, Folder 160-163)
  - Sage, William H. memorial fund, 1928-1929 (Box 13, Folder 164)
  - Sage Hall
    - circa 1924-1925 (Box 13, Folder 165)
    - Bower's Wing, 1930-1931 (Box 13, Folder 166-168)
    - Building and Blueprint, 1922-1923 (Box 13, Folder 169)
    - Dedication, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 170-171)
    - Equipment, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 172)
    - Furniture, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 173)
    - Inventories, 1923-1937 (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - School Funds - Gifts to Indow a Chair of Applied Forestry and Practical Lumbering, circa 1910 (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - Schools Having Forestry Courses, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - Secretary's Office
  - 1923 (Box 13, Folder 178)
  - circa 1932-1939 (Box 13, Folder 179-181)
  - Service Bureau
    - Correspondence, 1937-1940 (Box 14, Folder 182)
    - Repairs, 1930-1932 (Box 14, Folder 183-184)
    - Repairs etc., 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 185)
    - Yellow Ticket, 1919-1920 (Box 14, Folder 186)
  - Sheffield Scientific School
    - 1919-1920 (Box 14, Folder 187)
    - 1922-1923 (Box 14, Folder 188)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 14, Folder 189)
    - Machines borrowed from Yale Forestry School, 1916-1922 (Box 14, Folder 190)
  - Simsbury Forest - plans, Undated (Box 14, Folder 191)
  - Students' Army Training Corps., 1928 (Box 14, Folder 193)
  - T
    - 1925-1931 (Box 14, Folder 194)
    - 1933-1939 (Box 14, Folder 195-196)
  - Toumey Fund, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 197)
  - Treasurer's Office
    - Bills, 1922-1924 (Box 14, Folder 201)
    - Correspondence
      - 1923-1924 (Box 14, Folder 202)
      - 1924-1929 (Box 14, Folder 203)
      - 1930-1932 (Box 15, Folder 204)
      - 1932-1936 (Box 15, Folder 205-206)
    - Gifts and contributions, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 207)
    - Monthly Statements
      - 1919-1924 (Box 15, Folder 208-210)
      - 1932-1939 (Box 15, Folder 211-212)
  - Tropical America, Institute for Research in, etc., 1929-1932 (Box 15, Folder 213)
  - Tropical Forestry
    - circa 1911 (Box 15, Folder 214)
    - Correspondence, circa 1916-1917 (Box 15, Folder 215)
    - An outline Report, 1916-1920 (Box 15, Folder 216)
    - South America, Travel and related correspondence, circa 1916-1917 (Box 15, Folder 217)
    - Studies, circa 1916-1917 (Box 15, Folder 218)
    - Wood Specimens, circa 1928 (Box 15, Folder 219)
  - U, 1931-1939 (Box 15, Folder 220)
  - V
    - 1925-1932 (Box 15, Folder 221)
    - 1935-1939 (Box 15, Folder 222)
  - W
    - 1927-1932 (Box 15, Folder 223)
    - 1932-1939 (Box 16, Folder 224-225)
  - Wildlife, increase and preservation, Undated (Box 16, Folder 227)
  - Woolsey, Theodore Salisbury, Jr. -- Correspondence; Extract from his Will, 1922; 1936 (Box 16, Folder 229)
  - Y, 1928-1939 (Box 16, Folder 230)
  - Yale BA's who continued in Yale Forest School, -1917 (Box 16, Folder 231)
  - Yale School of Forestry (Yale Forestry School)
    - Alumni Association Executive Council, 1924-1933 (Box 16, Folder 232)
    - Class of 1906 - Notes from 1916 (Box 16, Folder 233)
    - Commencement Addresses etc., 1917-1919 (Box 16, Folder 234)
    - Courses in Forestry, or Preparatory to Forestry, circa 1906-1912 (Box 16, Folder 235)
    - Courses of Study - Individual Outlines, circa 1921-1923 (Box 16, Folder 236)
    - Courses on the Lumber Industry, Outline of, circa 1909 (Box 16, Folder 237)
    - Course in Pre-Forestry - Rearrangement of, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 238)
    - Course in Wildlife, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 239)
    - Degree Requests, 1907-1912 (Box 16, Folder 240)
    - Degree Requirements - Master of Forestry, Undated (Box 16, Folder 241)
    - Forest Club, 1911-1912 (Box 16, Folder 242)
    - Governing Board
      - 1908-1914 (Box 16, Folder 243)
      - Minutes, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 244)
      - 1915-1919 (Box 16, Folder 245)
    - Graduates of 1907; report of 1917 (Box 17, Folder 246)
    - Graduates, 1922; Summary 1925 (Box 17, Folder 247)
    - Graduates - Obituaries, Undated (Box 17, Folder 248)
    - Library, 1931-1935 (Box 17, Folder 249)
    - News Releases, circa 1921-1939 (Box 17, Folder 250)
    - Notices etc. to the Faculty, 1923-1939 (Box 17, Folder 251-252)
    - Organization, Undated (Box 17, Folder 253)
    - Organization, Future Plans, Curriculum, circa 1923 (Box 17, Folder 254)
    - Report of the School, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 255)
    - Research and Investigation, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 256)
    - Scholarships and Loans, 1921-1940 (Box 17, Folder 257-259)
    - Seminars, 1920-1921 (Box 18, Folder 260)
    - Silviculture, Chair of, Undated (Box 18, Folder 261)
    - Special Committee on School Affairs, circa 1936 (Box 18, Folder 262)
    - Speeches and Addresses, circa 1932-1940 (Box 18, Folder 263)
  - Yale Natural Preserve, 1925-1931 (Box 18, Folder 264-266)
  - Yale University - Reorganization, 1919 (Box 18, Folder 267-268)
  - Yale University Press - Manufacturing Department, 1936-1939 (Box 18, Folder 269)
  - Z, 1928-1939 (Box 18, Folder 210)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - 1910-1917 (Box 19, Folder 271-274)
    - 1919-1920 (Box 19, Folder 275)
    - 1920-1924 (Box 20, Folder 276-277)
    - 1927-1932 (Box 20, Folder 278)
    - 1930-1931 (Box 20, Folder 279)
    - circa 1930-1932 (Box 20, Folder 280)
    - circa 1923-1931 (Box 20, Folder 281)
    - circa 1928-1932 (Box 20, Folder 282)
  - Yale Corporation - Votes
    - 1919-1930 (Box 21, Folder 283)
    - circa 1930-1939 (Box 21, Folder 284)
- Reports from James W. Toumey, 1918-1921; Accession 1982-A-013
  - Reports to fellows and President, 1918-1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reports to Provost, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Reports and papers, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Records of Samuel J. Record, 1920-1946; Accession 1982-A-014
  - A, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agricultural Science-Program Suggested by E. W. Sinnott, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report t o the President-Samuel J. Record, 1939-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Appointments, Bureau of, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arboretum at Norfolk, CT-Development; Herbarium Specimen Loans, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arnold, Benjamin Walworth, Collection of Wooden Books, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - B, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Benner Fund, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Botanical Society of America-War Emergency Committee, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Budget, 1940-1946 (Box 1, Folder 11-16)
  - Bursar"s Office, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - C, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - C.C.C. Camps, establishment, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Chapman, H. H., 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Committee on School Forests, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Atation Fellowship, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - D, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Faculty, Memoranda, 1939-1945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Forest Service, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Forestry Education, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Graduate School, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - H, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - J, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - L, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - M, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Military-Defense Activities, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - N, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - News Releases, 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - O, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - P, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Personnel Office-Policies etc., 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Post-war Planning, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - R, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Rockefeller Foundation-Committee International Du Bois, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - S, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Secretary"s Office, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Secretary"s Office-Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Sheffield Scientific School, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Sheffield Scientific School-Biological Sciences, 1939-1945 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Silox-Stuart Memorial Tablet, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Speeches and Addresses, 1940-1946 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Student Concerns Considered by Faculty, 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - T, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - "Timbers of the New World"-memorandum of agreement re ownership of manuscript, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Treasurer"s Office
    - Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Monthly Statements, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Tropical Woods-Financial, 1929-1943 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Twentieth Engineers Fund, 1920-1940 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - University Health, Department of, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Vocational Training in Forestry-post-war, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Work Sheets, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Yale Dames, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Yale Forestry School
    - Alumni Association Executive Council, 1940-1945 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Endowment Need and Gifts to Income, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - News and Alumni Report, 1933-1945 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Policy, Plans during and After WWI, 1941-1945 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - American Creosoting Company Fellowship, 1935-1940 (Box 3, Folder 70-71)
  - Votes of the Yale Corporation concerning Staff Appointments, 1939-1945 (Box 3, Folder 72)
- Records of George A. Garratt, 1945-1969; Accession 1982-A-015
  - A, 1945-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Advertisements and Announcements, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Advisory Committee-Science, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Board-Yale University-Committee on Graduate and Professional Schools, 1945-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Records-Yale Forestry School, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 9-13)
  - American Foresters, Society of
    - 1945-1941 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Anniversaries of Yale Forestry School-50th and 60th, 1950, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Annual Reports-G. A. Garrett, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
  - Annual Reports to the President, 1945-1955 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Appointments, Bureau of
    - 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
    - 1956-1960 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - Army Contract: Research on the Vibrational Properties of Defect-Free Wood, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Atomic Energy Commission
    - Administration (See: Faculty Research), 1961-1967 (Box 4)
    - Expenditures (See: Faculty Research), 1961-1966 (Box 4)
    - Final Report (See: Faculty Research, I, 8), 1961-1966 (Box 4)
    - Progress Reports and Renewal Proposal (See: Faculty Research, I, 9), 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - B, 1946-1963 (Box 4, Folder 28-32)
  - Biological Sciences-Executive Committee Sheffield Scientific School, 1945-1956 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Botanical Investigation of the Woody Plants of Darien Province-Panama, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Budget, 1946-1956 (Box 4, Folder 35-43)
  - Building Plans, circa1945 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Building Plans-Greeley Memorial Lab, 1956-1959 (Box 5, Folder 45-47)
  - Buildings
    - Greeley Memorial Lab, 1960-1964 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Marsh Hall, Designation as a Landmark, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Sage Hall-Rules Governing Use, ?1954-1963 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Bulletins (of Yale Forestry School), 1956-1960 (Box 5, Folder 51-54)
  - Bursar"s Office, 1945-1962 (Box 5, Folder 55-58)
  - C, 1946-1963 (Box 6, Folder 59-63)
  - Chapman Fellowship Announcements, 1953- (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Chinese Students
    - Correspondence concerning Admissions to Yale Forestry School, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Connecticut Park and Forest Commission
    - Correspondence etc., 1949-1956 (Box 7, Folder 68-70)
    - Documents and Reports etc., 1949-1955 (Box 7, Folder 71-73)
    - Meetings, Agendae, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 74-75)
    - Reports, Auditor of Public Accounts etc., 1950-1954 (Box 7, Folder 76-78)
  - Connecticut State Graduate Scholarship Program, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Conservation, Academic Progxam of, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - D, 1946-1963 (Box 8, Folder 81-85)
  - Duke University Questionnaire concerning plant of Forestry School, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - E, 1946-1963 (Box 8, Folder 88-92)
  - Equipment Needs, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Exchange Bulletins, Agreements, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - F
    - 1946-1958 (Box 8, Folder 95-97)
    - 1959-1963 (Box 9, Folder 98-99)
  - Faculty, Memoranda, 1950-1959 (Box 9, Folder 100-102)
  - Faculty Research
    - Institute of Paper Chemistry, 1961-1965 (Box 9, Folder 103)
    - International Paper Company Foundation, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 104)
    - National Science Foundation-GB 3653, 1960-1965 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Fellowships, Assistantships, 1960-1961 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Field Instruction-Yale Forestry School (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Foreign Students Affairs, 1959-1962 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Foreign Students-Interschool Committee, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Forest Biology Program Finances, 1960-1963 (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - Forest Demands Study proposed by Weyerhaeuser, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Forest Fire Residence Project, 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Forest History, Society of, 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Forest Pathology Program-Economics course listing, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Forest Products Research Society
    - 1946-1957 (Box 10, Folder 115-116)
    - 1960 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Forest Service
    - 1946-1950 (Box 10, Folder 118-119)
    - 1950-1961 (Box 11, Folder 120-123)
  - U.S. (See: Mergen, folders 175-177)
  - Forestry Abstracts-Card File, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - Forestry Club (See: Mergen, folder 178)
  - Forestry Education, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Forestry School Executives, Council of, 1945-1965 (Box 11, Folder 126-130)
  - Forests under Management of Yale Forestry School
    - 1949 (Box 11, Folder 131)
    - 1950-1956 (Box 12, Folder 132)
  - G, 1946-1963 (Box 12, Folder 133-137)
  - Genetics-Ph.D. Program, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - Goodyear, Charles W., Scholarships-Forestry, circa1949 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - Graduate School
    - 1946-1961 (Box 12, Folder 143-146)
    - Department of Forestry, 1947-1954 (Box 12, Folder 147)
    - Form Letters, circa1956 (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Graduation, General (See: Mergen, folder 191)
  - Greeley Memorial Laboratory
    - Construction Appointments and Preliminary Plans, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 152)
    - Construction, 1958-1959 (Box 13, Folder 153-154)
    - Specifications, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 155-156)